Guide to the Ivan E. Phillips, Class of 1956, Yale College, Papers Documenting his Undergraduate Courses
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Ivan E. Phillips, Class of 1956, Yale College, papers documenting his undergraduate courses
1945-1956
RU 916
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.25
The papers consist of the lecture notes, examinations, syllabi and handouts documenting Ivan Phillips's undergraduate courses taken between 1952-1956, including courses in history, economics, and science. Also included are several grade school notebooks.
Phillips, Ivan E.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 47 (YRG 47), Collections documenting teaching and learning in Yale academic programs.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The materials were a gift of Ivan E. Phillips.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of the lecture notes, examinations, syllabi and handouts documenting Ivan Phillips's undergraduate courses taken between 1952-1956, including courses in history, economics, and science. Also included are several grade school notebooks.
Arrangement
The papers are arranged chronologically.
Biographical / Historical
Ivan Edward Phillips was born to Lazarus and Rosalie Idelson Phillips on May 10, 1934 in Montreal, Quebec. He prepared at the Selwyn House School in Montreal and at Deerfield before entering Yale in 1952. He graduated in 1956 as a history major. He was a member of Silliman College and Chi Psi Fraternity as well as a member of the Record Board from 1953-1955.
Phillips, Ivan E.; Yale University -- Students
- Records, Series I
  - Yale College courses
    - Economics 10, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Linguistics 20a, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 2 - 3)
    - Chemistry 12, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Economics 10b, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - English 15, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - French 32, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - History 10b, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - History of Art 12, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Spanish 12, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Classical Civilization 23, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 11 - 12)
    - Economics 27b, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 13 - 14)
    - History 23b, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 15 - 16)
    - History 50, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 17 - 18)
    - History 59a, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 19 - 20)
    - History of Art 12, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Linguistics 20b, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 22 - 23)
    - Political Science 63a, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 24 - 25)
    - Spanish 12b, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Classical Civilization 20, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 27 - 28)
    - History 59b, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 29 - 30)
    - History 67, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 31 - 32)
    - History 50b, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 33 - 34)
    - History of Art 41a, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - History of Art 63, [1955] (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Italian 32b, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 37 - 38)
    - Philosophy 30a, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Religion 28, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 40 - 41)
    - Classical Civilization 20b, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 42 - 43)
    - History 46, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - History 46b, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 45 - 46)
    - History 53b, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 47 - 48)
    - History 67a, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - History 67b, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Philosophy 23b, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 51 - 53)
    - Philosophy 46a, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 54 - 55)
  - Grade school notebooks
    - Extra Spelling, Circa 1945 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Form II English/History, Circa 1945 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Form II Essay, Circa 1945 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Form II French, Circa 1945 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Form II Geography, Circa 1945 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Form II Latin, Circa 1945 (Box 5, Folder 61)